[Music]
Today we are going to go to Italy and do
espresso compana in the ninja
[Music]
creamy. Any Italians out there?
Apologies for pronunciation. Espresso
compana is espresso with cream. And
that's where the cafe pan gets their
name from in the US. Uh cream. So, what
is espresso compana? It is just a shot
of espresso with cream on top. It's
delicious. I mean, it's really, really
nice. It's um I don't think it's super
common because, you know, Italians like
to drink their coffee pretty pretty
bare. Um but I I love it. It's a real
nice treat every, you know, hour of the
day. But we're going to turn it into ice
cream. We're going to use the Ninja
Creamy. We're going to use the deluxe.
Why not? because I want a bigger portion
of it. So, as this is an Italian video,
we're going to do espresso gelato with a
top layer of stabilized whipped cream.
So, what are we going to need for the
espresso gelato? You are going to need
490 g of milk. 2% or whole milk is
absolutely fine. 245 g of whipping
cream. Double cream is absolutely fine
in the UK. Heavy cream is fine in the
US. We're going to use 115 g of
alulose, 50 g of skim milk powder, 100 g
of espresso, and and I'm going to use a
stabilizer. And I'm going to
use 3 and 12 g of stabilizer blend. If
you want to use gua gum or zantham gum,
you might need to drop that down to
about 3 g. You can also use xylitol for
this. We're not going sugar-free,
obviously, cuz we're using dairy. So,
the lactose, which is sugar, will show
up as sugar, but this is super super low
sugar. I'll put percentages on the
screen now so you will know. But let's
get things weighed out and
going. So, the first thing is our milk,
which is 490
g. Next is our cream, 245 g. Cup
measurements on the screen as well.
115 g of alulos.
This is the alios I'm using
today. Really super granular. 50 g of
skim milk powder. Because we're using a
stabilizer, we're going to put our skim
milk powder into a little container
first. So, I'm going to use a blend
stabilizer, my own blend. Going to use 2
g of
it. If you use a cold processed
stabilizer, you don't need to heat this
up super super high. But as mine needs
to be heated up, we're going to heat it
up in it all goes together. If you're
using stabilizers, you mix them with
either your skim milk powder or your
sugar to break the powder apart so that
it doesn't clump when you add it to
liquid. And finally, we need 100 g of
espresso. You make this however you want
to make it. Whether you use a mocka pot,
whe you've got an espresso machine, you
got pods, use whatever you got. doesn't
make any
[Music]
difference. And there's our espresso in
there. Now, let's get it on heat. We're
going to bring this up cuz my stabilizer
needs completely heating. So, we're
going to bring it up to 85C, 180F. Make
sure that it's fully hydrated and
cooked. With our base heated
up, we're going to really push that
coffee flavor. Now, you can do it in two
ways. You can use coffee extract or you
can use instant coffee
powder. Just buy this for using an ice
cream. It's incredible. Plus, it's
easier to balance cuz you're not adding
so much water. So, what we're going to
do, we're going to
add a whole tablespoon of that instant
coffee
powder into our base. as it's still nice
and hot. That will
just dissolve. If you're like me and you
like super intense coffee and coffee ice
cream, do add that. Don't just increase
the amount of espresso cuz that's just
water. Just basically pure water you're
adding into your mix. That is why I
really like using this
in ice creams.
It's much easier to balance. Doesn't
change your freezing point. Doesn't
affect your ice crystal formation. So,
with that now done, we're going to split
this between our two ninja creamy
tubs and we're going to pop them in the
freezer. We're going to put them in
there for a good few hours. We want this
to harden off before we do the top
layer. So, let's get that in the freezer
and I'll come back when we're ready. So,
as our ice cream is almost frozen, I
mean, in respect, it's not. It's still
liquid in the middle, but it's it's
frozen enough for us to carry on. So,
we're going to do the top layer. We're
going to open up our whipping cream.
Again, you can use higher fat cream to
whip. That is absolutely fine. Will help
if I open the cream on the right side,
but hey, there we go. So, we're going to
add 500 g, 500 ml of our cream into this
container. In here we
have vanilla sugar. This is just normal
sugar with the old vanilla pods from
making vanilla extract stored inside
like that. You can see the vanilla pods
in there and it just sits in there. I
let it sit for about a month just to
really become flavorful. But there's so
much vanilla flavor come out and of the
liquid come out that the sugar's gone
solid. So you have to kind of scrape it
around.
But what we have is super vanilla
flavored and scented sugar. So, we're
going to go 500 g of our cream into
here. I don't have a fancy electric
whisk. So, I'm going to whisk this by
hand. So, just keep going. We're going
to get nice and full. One little
ingredient. We're going to add the
science part. Guar gum. You can add
zantham gum as
well, but it needs to be a cold
processed stabilizer, otherwise it won't
work. So, we are simply going to take
it's really about a large 1/4 teaspoon.
So, we're looking at about 2 g 1 and 1/2
g of goo gum. And let's get that in
there.
Go. All right. So, we're about there.
We're not super whipping this to the
point where it stands on the end of a
spoon. That's not the texture we're
going for. We're adding about 50% in
air. And what we get is this really nice
fudgy kind of consistency. So this is
like a a thick melted
chocolate. So once you get to that
stage,
stop because you're very close to that
whip. It takes seconds to go from
perfect to over whipped. So, we've got
our consistency
here. Let's
get There we go.
Perfect. See, just dripping enough.
Let's get our tubs out the freezer. So,
here are our
containers. Like I said, they're not
frozen properly yet, but what we are
going to do, we are simply going to load
up our cream and just gently lay it on
the top.
Like so. Don't let it
drop into
that ice cream
base. If you want to leave your ice
cream a bit longer to harden off, that
is absolutely fine. Do that. We're going
to make sure our cream goes right to the
top of our line. So, with our coffee
gelato now topped with our delicious
vanilla flavored whipped cream, going to
get those back in the freezer overnight.
on top of your vanilla sugar. You can
absolutely add vanilla extract to this.
My vanilla sugar is so strong, I just
don't need to add anymore. But feel
free. I've got some more here. Time to
make me an espresso
[Music]
compana. Double espresso. Mix it up.
Drink it as it is. Do what you
[Music]
want. Got a little bit of cream left
here. I'm going to put this in the
fridge until
tomorrow. Minus that bit. All right,
let's get this spun
up or not.
[Music]
Okie dokie. Let's see how this one
turned
out. Okay, step one. Step one is really
good.
Good. Step two is cuz this is pretty
much just
cream. It kind of goes crumbly. Let me
show you. It goes crumbly on the top. As
this is the deluxe, we can just do the
top. And we're going to put it on light
ice cream
setting. There we go.
The light ice cream setting spins much
faster than the ice cream standard ice
cream setting, which turns the top back
into a really creamy
texture. And that's important if you're
using cream. Let me just try this. Yes.
[Music]
If you want to dig down, you two layered
ice cream. So the top you've got that
spun cream which is
delicious and then in the bottom half
you've got that coffee gelato which man
super super good. Some of the leftover
cream. So, the amount of cream in this
recipe gives you enough for this. I'm
just going to eat that. Could eat that
for
years. Let's try this. Oh, that's so
good. Super super
creamy. Perfect texture. Incredible
mouth feel. Having that cream scoop on
top brings it right back to how it
should be.
Obviously, as I mentioned before, the
coffee base has got cream in it as it's
a gelato. So, it's not exactly the same
as espresso. If we wanted to do
espresso, we would have to do espresso
sorbet. Absolutely doable, though. Oh,
that's right up there. That's right up
there in my top 10 ice
creams. Make sure you've got some of
that whipped stabilized cream left over.
Add it on top of your scoop of this
incredible espresso compana gelato with
whipped cream top made in the Ninja
Creamy. If you're going to make this in
a churn machine, churn your gelato, add
your cream after. Literally can't tell
you how good this
is. One of the best ninja creamy ice
creams I've
tasted. That double layer. Make sure you
spin that cream layer. Again, this is
the Ninja Creamy Deluxe. So spin the top
half which has your cream in it on the
light ice cream spins much much faster.
You can spin it on sorbet setting as
well. That brings that cream back into
the same texture that we're looking for.
On the first spin that top layer will go
really crumbly and it will look horrible
because it's just cream and a little bit
of sugar. Nothing else. Cream does not
like to be processed like ice cream. So
thanks very much for watching. Don't
forget to like and subscribe. No idea
what I'm going to do next week. So, it's
going to be a surprise to everyone. Take
care. See you later.
[Music]